<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Where in a proclamation (lately by us published) for considerations therein expressed, we prescribed a course whereby the complaints of our people might be taken away, ...</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1603</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B12682</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 8319</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 506.h.10[14]</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99892738</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99892738</idno>
            <idno type="VID">187110</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B12682)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 187110)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C7:1[14])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Where in a proclamation (lately by us published) for considerations therein expressed, we prescribed a course whereby the complaints of our people might be taken away, ...</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1603-1625 : James I)</author>
                  <author>James I, King of England, 1566-1625.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>by Robert Barker, printer to the Kings Most excellent Maiestie.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>anno Dom. 1603.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>At end of text: Greenwich the 16. day of June, in the first yeere of our reigne of England, France, and Ireland, and in the sixe and thirtieth of Scotland.</note>
                  <note>Announcing that the patent for tin has been surrendered. Cf. STC.</note>
                  <note>In this edition line 3 of text ends: iust-.</note>
                  <note>Title from opening lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Tin --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Patent laws and legislation --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  James I, 1603-1625 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:187110:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> By the King.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Here in a Proclamation (lately by vs publiſhed) for conſiderations therein expreſſed, We preſcribed a courſe whereby the complaints of our people might be taken away, if the ſame ſhould appeare to be iuſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly grounded; Hauing now ſince that time receiued particular infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation, that a Grant to certain Patentees for the ſole preemption and tranſportation of Tinne, was very inconuenient and full of grieuance to our louing Subiects: Wee, after long debate thereof before our ſelfe and our Priuie Councell, where obiections of either ſide were made, and where the inconueniences were layed open, Haue reſolued not onely to conſider how the generalitie of our Subiects might bee relieued in ſuſpenſion of this Graunt, but how the ſame might be done without any iniuſtice to any particuler perſon, who is intereſſed there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in by vertue of Letters Patents vnder the great Seale of England, whereof wee neuer intend to ſeeke any courſe of reuocation, but by an ordinary courſe of Iuſtice, in which all our people are equally intereſſed. In which reſpect, hauing commaunded the Lords and others of our Priuie Councell to call before them the Patentees, and then to offer them all ſuch triall for the maintenance of that Patent, as the Iuſtice of this our Realme affordeth, The ſaid Patentees haue rather yeelded in their owne duetie and diſcretions, to ſurrender the Patent, then to goe about to maintaine it: Whereof wee thought it fit that all our good Subiects ſhould take no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice, as an Argument of our continuall care and deſire to doe all things, which tend to the reliefe of our people in any thing, whereby they receiue any maner of oppreſſion, as long as they ſhall duetifully and orderly appeale vnto vs for the ſame.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Giuen at our Mannour of Greenwich <date>the <hi>16.</hi> day of June, in the first yeere of our Reigne of England, France, and Jreland, And in the ſixe and thirtieth of Scotland.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <closer>God ſaue the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>¶ Imprinted at London by Robert Barker, Printer to the Kings moſt excellent Maieſtie. Anno Dom. 1603.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
